# Karmegam V

# Krishnagiri, Tamil Nadu, India

#### **PROFILE**

As a dedicated Software Engineer, I bring a rich tapestry of experience and a passion for innovation to Zoho. My journey, from humble beginnings as a first-generation graduate to shaping young minds as an Instructor, has prepared me to excel in the dynamic world of software engineering.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Algomox Private Limited, Bengaluru Software Engineer

Nov 2022 - Present

Algomox pvt Ltd positions itself as high-quality value-added software company that helps enterprises accelerate their artificial intelligence for IT operations (AIOps) transformation. Algomox platform is truly innovative with patent-pending technology.

- Developed and maintained Golang-based backend services and APIs for Algomox's core applications, ensuring high performance and scalability.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including front-end developers and product managers
- Implemented unit tests to maintain code quality and reliability. Optimized database queries and data storage.
- Resolved critical production issues promptly, minimizing downtime and ensuring a seamless user experience.

# Skill development centre - (RKMPTC), Chennai instructor

Jul 2020 - Oct 2022 (2 year 4 months)

- Experienced in ZOHO creator, ZOHO MDM, ZOHO Sites,
- Teaching and Server Administration,
- Network monitoring, IIS and Project coordination.

### **EDUCATION**

Tamilnadu Open university, Chennai -Master of Computer Applications – MCA, Jun 2018 - May 2020

# **Periyar University, SVMC**, Uthangarai Bachelor of Computer Applications – BCA

Jun 2014 - Apr 2017

## **PROJECTS**

- Azure AD and On-premise AD Automation using Graph and REST APIs,
- Windows Patch Management tool using golang
- Face mask detection,
- Automated for PFsense firewall reporting.

**8344355512** 

vkarmegam97@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/karmegam-v



https://github.com/VKARMEGAM

#### **SKILLS**

- ✓ Golang Gin, Gorilla Mux, REST APIs, Micro services, Concurrency, Nats and Websockets. AWS and Azure.
- Python Flask, REST APIS, Numpy, TK, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, version controls. automation.
- ✓ IAVA
- ✓ Machine Learning Basics,
- ✓ SQL , Cassandra
- ✓ Git, Bash, Powershell.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

# Softlogic Academy -SLADS072020

- Machine Learning
- Python Programming

Networking CISCO Academy

# Cisco Networking Academy -

# CCNA R&S: [56362465]

- ✓ Introduction to Networks
- ✓ Routing and Switching
- ✓ Scaling Networks
- ✓ Connecting

#### **HDCS from TCSD**

# DCA from CCS

## **KEY SKILLS**

- ✓ Self Learning,
- ✓ Listening Skill,
- ✓ Good Communication,
- ✓ Get attached with people,
- ✓ Trustworthy & Open-minded

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, Tamil.